A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Administration, 1995-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- Series VIII. Public Broadcasting Board records, 2006-2009., Extent: .55 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 48-49)
  - Correspondence and supporting documentation, 2006. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and supporting documentation, 2007. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and supporting documentation, 2008. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and supporting documentation, 2009. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting records, 2007 March 22. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting records, 2007 May 24. (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting records, 2008 September 11. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Board meeting records, 2009 June 9. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Board meeting records, 2009 September 22. (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Applications for Community Service Grants for Public Radio, FY2007-FY2009. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Applications for Community Service Grants for Public Television, FY2007-FY2009. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Applications for Operating Grants for Radio Reading Services, FY2007-FY2009. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Contracts for Instructional Telecommunications Services, FY2008. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Contracts for Instructional Telecommunications Services, FY2009. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Contract statements, 2008 Nov. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Contract statements, 2009. (Box 49, Folder 7)
- Series IX. Real Property and Capital Outlay records, 1995-2009., Extent: 3.85 cubic feet (11 boxes). (Box 50-60)
  This series is housed in 11 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by subject. This series includes correspondence, decision briefs, leases, legal records and reports that document the funding, maintenance and operation of certain state builidngs as well as other real property issues handled by the Department of General Services. This series includes files related to the renovation of the State Capitol and files inherited from the previous administration related to the Governor's Real Estate Initiative. Many files document the disposition of certain state property, including the Ballard property in Norfolk and the St. Asaph property in Alexandria, while others involve the proposed demolition and renovation of the Eighth and Ninth Street office building and the opposition to the demolition by the Alliance to Conserve Old Richmond Neighborhoods (ACORN).
  - 8th and 9th Street buildings, 2004-2009. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - 8th and 9th Street buildings - ACORN v. COV, Plaintiff's submission (v. 1), 2005. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - 8th and 9th Street buildings - ACORN v. COV, Plaintiff's submission (v. 2), 2005. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Appraisal, 2005. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Contracts, 2007. (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Documentation (folder 1 of 3), 2007 compiled. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Documentation (folder 2 of 3), 2007 compiled. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Documentation (folder 3 of 3), 2007 compiled. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Maps and photographs, 2007 compiled. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Ballard Binder - Meeting notes, 2007 March 2. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Correspondence, 2005. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Correspondence, 2006. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Correspondence, 2007. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Decision brief (v. 2 of 2) [v. 1 not located], 2007 November. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Decision brief, 2007 December 4. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Decision brief binder (v. 2) (folder 1 of 2), 2007-2008. (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Decision brief binder (v. 2) (folder 2 of 2), 2007-2008. (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Division of Real Estate Service documentation binder, 1995-1997. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 January-February 26. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 February 27-28. (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 March 1-7. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 March 9-12. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 March 13-16. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 March 19-20. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 March 21-30. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 April. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 May. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 June. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation - Miscellaneous (binder), 2007 March-June. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 July 10-12. (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 July 13. (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 July 16-19. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 July 20-31. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 August. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 October. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 November. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Emails and other documentation (binder), 2007 December. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Fort Norfolk Plaza plans, 2007. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: List of major documents for closing, 2007. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Maps and photographs, 2007. (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Norfolk City binder, 2007 February 23. (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Real estate purchase documentation, 2007. (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Report - Atlantic City, Norfolk, VA: A Redevelopment Plan, 2002 March. (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Ballard Property, Norfolk: Site characterization report, 2007 April 6. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - DMV Customer Service Center - Roanoke, 2008. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Pelham Confederate Memorial Chapel, 2008-2009. (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Public-Private Education Facilities and Infrastructure Act (PPEA), 2006-2009. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate Initiative: Agency Roundtable, 2004 September 22. (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Real Estate Initiative: Cabinet briefing, 2004 June 7. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Real Estate Initiative: CB Richard Ellis Consultants (CBRE) binder, 2003-2004. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Real Estate Initiative: CBRE Proposal for Consulting Services for Management of the Commonwealth's Real Estate Portfolio, 2003. (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Real Estate Initiative: CBRE Presentation for Consulting Services for Management of the Commonwealth's Real Estate Portfolio, n.d.. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate Initiative: CBRE Proposed Space Standards and Recommendations, 2004 September 14. (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Real Estate Initiative: CBRE Phase II Report (preliminary draft), 2005 February 1. (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate Initiative: Real Estate Portfolio Project (Zorn binder), 2004. (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI binder v. 1 (folder 1 of 6), 2004. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI binder v. 1 (folder 3 of 6), 2004. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI binder v. 1 (folder 4 of 6), 2004. (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI binder v. 1 (folder 5 of 6), 2004. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI binder v. 1 (folder 6 of 6), 2004. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate Initiative: REI Overview presentation, 2008 January 17. (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - St. Asaph Street Property, Alexandria, 2004-2006. (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - St. Asaph Street Property, Alexandria, 2006-2007. (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - St. Asaph Street Property, Alexandria - Proposal, 2006. (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Southeastern Virginia Training Center (SEVTC), 2009. (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Space planning for the Dept. of Housing and Community Development, 2007-2008. (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Capitol Square Preservation Council, 2006-2009. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Legislation (SB 693), 2006. (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Report: An Ediface of First Rate Dignity - Pre-design assessment report, 2003. (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Report: The Renovation of the Virginia State Capitol Building - Scope of Work Final Draft Statement, 2003 June 30. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Report: Virginia State Capitol, 2007. (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Virginia Capitol Foundation, 2004-2007. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Virginia Capitol Foundation, 2007-2009. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Virginia Capitol Preservation Foundation, 2005. (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - State Capitol Renovation - Window treatments for Governor's Office, 2007. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University/Oregon Hill Neighborhood Association, 2007 April-May. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University/Oregon Hill Neighborhood Association, 2007 June-September. (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Bio-Technology Research Park/ Division of Consolidated Laboratory Services, 2007. (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Western State Hospital, 2007-2008. (Box 58, Folder 1)
- Series X. Special Projects: Civil Rights Memorial, 2006-2009., Extent: .80 cubic feet. (Box 61-62, 67)
  This series is housed in 2 boxes and is arranged alphabetically. This series includes correspondence, meeting records, programs, reports, visitor registers, and budget and planning information that document the commissioning of the Civil Rights Memorial in Capitol Square and preparations for the Civil Rights Memorial Dedication and Unveiling and the accompanying educational symposium. Much of this work was carried out by the Capitol Square Civil Rights Memorial Foundation, which was established to memorialize and honor the courage and fortitude of those Virginians involved in the Civil Rights Movement. The memorial sculpture acknowledges and celebrates those who fought to desegregate Virginia's schools.
  - Capitol Square Civil Rights Memorial Foundation - Articles of Incorporation, 2006 January 17. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Commemorative coin, 2009. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Contract with sculptor Stanley Bleifeld (copy), 2006 May 2. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2007. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2009. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Dedication Celebration Education Symposium, 2008 July 20-21. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Financial and fundraising documentation, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Literary Contest and Moton Museum Awards, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Master Program Plan - Correspondence with Honorary Co-chairs, 2008 May 2. (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Master Program Plan - Deed of Gift (draft), 2008. (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Master Program Plan - Planning Committee reports, 2008 May-June. (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Master Program Plan - Talking points, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Master Program Plan - Resource Management, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Master Program Plan - Dedication Ceremony and Symposium, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Master Program Plan - Security, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Master Program Plan - External Communications, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Master Program Plan - Theatrical Production, 2008. (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Memorial molds, 2008. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 2008. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of monument model, 2006. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Registration, 2008. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Virginia State Capitol Civil Rights Memorial Celebration Joint Committee meeting, 2008 June 10. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Visitor registers - Civil Rights Memorial dedication (3 v.), 2008 July 20-21. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Volunteers, 2008. (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Series XI. Special Projects: Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority (FMFADA), 2006-2009., Extent: .5 cubic feet. (Box 62-63)
  This series is housed in 2 boxes and is arranged alphabetically. This series includes correspondence, agreements, and meeting records, which include agendas, minutes, budgetary information, and presentation materials that document the work of the Fort Monroe Federal Area Development Authority (FMFADA). Located along the Chesapeake Bay within the city limits of Hampton, Fort Monroe was an Army base that was desinated for closure pursuant to the 2005 Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission Report. When the base closed, the land, buildings, and infrastructure assets transferred to the Commonwealth and this necessitated a redevelopment and reuse plan. FMFADA, a politial subdivision of the Commonwealth of Virginia and local redevelopment authority, was established to determine how best to manage the historic resources, preserve and protect the open space, and ensure the economic sustainability at Fort Monroe. FMFADA was comprised of 18 members, including Hampton residents, state government officials (including the Secretary of Administration), legislative members, and outside experts.
  - FMFADA binder, 2006-2007. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records, 2007 May 21. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records, 2008 April 28. (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records, 2008 September 19. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records, 2009 March 19. (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records, 2009 July 16. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records (folder 1 of 2), 2009 September 24. (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - FMFADA Board meeting records (folder 2 of 2), 2009 September 24. (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Series XII. Special Projects: Freedmen's Bureau records, 2006-2009., Extent: .2 cubic feet (2 folders). (Box 64)
  This series is housed in 1 box and is arranged alphabetically. This series includes correspondence, reports, news clippings and presentations that document efforts to digitize and index the Virginia Freedmen's Bureau records as part of the Virginia Freedmen Project. The Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, also known as the Freedmen's Bureau, was established by the War Dept. by an act of Congress on March 3, 1865, and was responsible for the supervision and management of all matters relating to refugees and freedmen and of the lands abandoned or seized during the Civil War. Between 1865-1872, the Bureau united families, legalized marriages, and provided relief services including food, shelter, education, job training and placement, and legal services. These records, including those of the Virginia Field Offices, were filmed by the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and afterwards the film was scanned by the Genealogical Society of Utah (GSU) in order to create digital images. The Virginia Freedmen's Project, led by the Black History Museum and Cultural Center of Virginia in conjunction with researchers from the Virginia Family History Centers, recruited, trained and coordinated volunteers to extract and index information from the scanned images in an effort to make these records more readily accessible to researchers. The Virginia project served as a pilot for subsequent projects in other Southern states.
  - Freedmen's Bureau records, 2006-2009. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Freedmen's Bureau records - Background information, 2006. (Box 64, Folder 2)
- Series XIII. Special Projects: Higher Education Restructuring, 2006-2009., Extent: .75 cubic feet (3 boxes). (Box 64-66)
  This series is housed in 3 boxes and is arranged alphabetically. This series includes correspondence, reports, agreements, expenditure analyses, SWAM procurement plans, and memoranda of understanding that document the implementation of the Virginia Restructured Higher Education Financial and Administrative Operations Act of 2005. This act provided public colleges and universities with more operational and administrative autonomy than other state agencies in exchange for a renewed commitment to meet higher education goals and performance measures. The Restructuring Act required all institutions to develop six-year academic, financial and enrollment plans to meet state goals. The Secretary of Administration's interest in the project was for the most part related to procurement (DGS), staff turnover (DHRM) and SWAM (DMBE) issues.
  - Higher Education Restructuring, 2007-2009. (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Christopher Newport University, 2008. (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - George Mason University, 2006-2009. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - James Madison University, 2008-2009. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Longwood University, 2008-2009. (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Norfolk State University, 2008. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Old Dominion University, 2008-2009. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Radford University, 2008-2009. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Richard Bland College, 2008. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - University of Mary Washington, 2008. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - University of Virginia, 2008-2009. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Commonwealth University, 2005-2009. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Commonwealth University Management Agreement, 2007 March. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Commonwealth University Management Agreement, 2007 November. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Community College System (VCCS), 2007-2008. (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Community College System (VCCS), 2009 February. (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Community College System (VCCS), 2009 March-May. (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Community College System (VCCS), 2009 September-December. (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Military Institute, 2008-2009. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia State University, 2008. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - Virginia Tech, 2007-2009. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Higher Education Restructuring - William and Mary, 2007-2009. (Box 66, Folder 4)
- Oversize, 2006-2009. (Box 68)